[Music]
the invisible stitch also known as the
ladder slip blind or hidden stitch is a
commonly used hand sewing stitch in this
example I'm using it to sew close the
opening on a pillow cover before you
begin iron or hand press the fabric
where you want the seam to be thread the
needle and make a knot at the end I'm
doubling up the thread for extra
strength bring the needle up through one
of the ironed edges so the knot is
hidden then go to the opposite side and
slide the needle through the top of the
fold so you pick up a little bit of
fabric next go directly across to the
other side and do the same thing repeat
this a couple more times the trick to
this stitch is when you go from side to
side go straight across so the thread is
perpendicular to the folds the thread
will start to look like the rungs on a
ladder then when you pull the thread
taut the stitches will disappear
continue this process down the opening
pulling the thread taut every couple of
stitches when you get to the end pick up
a bit of fabric like before this time
bring the needle through the loop of
thread so you form a knot then repeat
this going through the knot you just
made do this once more just to make sure
it's extra secure finally to hide the
tail of the thread go down through the
knot out the side of the fabric and snip
the thread and that's it the stitches
are just about invisible
[Music]